To compare DataFrames with Spark SQL,
为了比较 DataFrames 与 Spark SQL 的异同之处
let's walk through the same data wrangling and examples that you'd covered.
让我们再走一遍和之前相同数据处理流程
Though, we'll use a different section of the music streaming logs,
但这次我们会使用音乐日志的另一个部分
so our results will vary slightly.
所以我们的结果会略有不同
As you can see, we're working with the same form of data.
如你所见 我们使用数据形式和之前是一样的
It has the same schema as before.
框架和之前也相同
But unlike before, we have to create a temporary view of the DataFrame.
但与之前不同的是 我们必须创建一个 DataFrame 的临时视图
This effectively creates a temporary SQL table from the DataFrame,
这可以迅速地从 DataFrame 中创建一个临时 SQL 表
enabling you to make the same queries that you'd write if
这样你就可以进行
you were using a database like Postgres or MySQL.
像在 Postgres 或 MySQL 中的查询了
We do this by using the create or replace temp view function.
我们用 createOrReplaceTempView 这个函数来建表
As you might guess, this will create a view if it doesn't already exist,
你可能猜到了 如果视图尚不存在 这将创建一个新视图
or update the existing one if the underlying DataFrame changed.
当视图已经存在 如果底层数据有更新 就会更新视图
Unlike a database table, this view is temporary.
与数据库表不同 这个视图是临时的
If you end the session by closing the notebook,
如果关闭笔记本结束本次操作
you'll have to rerun this function before you can write queries.
在查询之前 你必须重新运行此函数
With the view setup, here's an example of a Spark SQL query.
视图设置完成后 这里有个 Spark SQL 查询的示例
But, remember the lazy evaluation.
但是 还记得惰性评估吗
You'll need to use either collect or show to force Spark
你必须使用 collect 或 show 来
to take action on the data, and show you results.
强制 Spark对数据进行处理 并显示结果
You can write simple SQL queries using the inline notation.
你可以用内联的方式写一些简单的SQL查询
But I prefer to use three apostrophes to write
但我更喜欢用三个撇号 ''' 来写多行的内联查
multi inline queries and make the SQL easier to read.
这样的 SQL 更易于阅读
This is the same notation you'd use to make multi-line comments in Python.
这和Python中进行多行注释的符号相同
As you can see, you can run the same calculations with
如你所见 你可以用
Spark SQL as you could with DataFrames.
Spark SQL 进行与 DataFrames 相同的计算
Though, the syntax is slightly different.
虽然 语法上略有不同
For example, use distinct instead of dropped duplicates.
例如 使用 distinct 而不是删除重复项
Another small difference is that UDFs have to be registered
另一个小差异是 你必须先注册 UDF
before they can be used.
才能使用它
Though this is very similar to the way you would define a UDF with DataFrames.
不过 UDF 的写法和你在 DataFrames 定义 UDF 的方式非常相似
Just like DataFrames, you can easily convert
就像 DataFrames 一样 你可以非常方便的
the results of your queries into Pandas DataFrames,
把查询结果转换为 Pandas DataFrames
and use all the features in libraries that come with Pandas.
并使用 Pandas 附带的库中的所有功能
Ultimately, Spark SQL offers nearly the same functionality of DataFrames.
Spark SQL 提供了和 DataFrame 几乎相同的功能
Which one you use is mostly a matter of preference.
至于你想用哪个 完全取决于你的偏好了
Spark SQL is great for users and teams who know
如果团队或用户更熟悉 SQL 而不是 pandas
SQL better than they know Pandas.
那 Spark SQL 就非常适合了
Whichever API you prefer,
无论你喜欢哪种API
it's a good idea to choose one,
选好一个后
and practice it consistently for the rest of this course.
在余下的课程里都要勤加练习
It's better to learn the tips and tricks of one API,
比起在不同 API 中来回切换
rather than switching back and forth.
不如好好学习一个 API 的各种提示和技巧